

☑ Ishen595@connect.hkust-gz.edu.cn

\(+86(18813121790)

I am Luyao Shen, a Ph.D. student at Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (Guangzhou) under the supervision of Prof. Mingming Fan and Prof. Pan Hui. My current research interests include Human-Computer Interaction, User Experience (UX) Design, and Virtual Reality (VR).

EDUCATION

Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (Guangzhou)	
Ph.D. in Computational Media and Arts	📛 2022-Current
University of Science and Technology Beijing	
Master of Art	2 017.09-2020.01
University of Science and Technology Beijing	
Bachelor of Engineering	Ö 2013.09-2017.06
PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE	
Betterlab	
User Experience (UX) designer	= 2022.03-2022.09
Institute of Software, Chinese Academy of Sciences	
HCI Research Assistant	\tau 2019.09-2021.05

PUBLICATIONS

- Chutian Jiang, Yanjun Chen, Mingming Fan, Liuping Wang, Luyao Shen, Nianlong Li, Wei Sun, Yu Zhang, Feng Tian, Teng Han. "Douleur: Creating Pain Sensation with Chemical Stimulant to Enhance User Experience in Virtual Reality" Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies (IMWUT), 2021
- Nianlong Li, Han-Jong Kim, Luyao Shen, Feng Tian, Teng Han, Xing-Dong Yang, Tek-Jin Nam. "HapLinkage: Prototyping Haptic Proxies for Virtual Hand Tools Using Linkage Mechanism" Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST), 2020

AWARDS

• ACM UIST 2020 Honorable Mention Award

2020

• University of Science and Technology Beijing Scholarship

2018-2020